Lynda Foster

lyndabrf@gmail.com | Phone | Github | LinkedIn | Burbank, CA

SUMMARY

Cloud Engineer with a BS Computer Science, a specialization in Salesforce technologies, and a background in DevOps.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java | React | SQL | Python | Bash

Web/API: JavaScript | HTML | CSS | Bootstrap | Regex | Postman | Swagger | XML **DevOps:** AWS | Terraform | Jenkins | Ansible | Kubernetes | Ubuntu | Docker

EXPERIENCE

Salesforce - San Francisco, CA | Developer Support Engineer | 05/2023 - Present

- Provide subject matter expertise in for Government Service Cloud applications
- Created and maintained systems documentation for support processes and procedures
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to identify and resolve client issues

Environment: Apex, Visualforce, Splunk, Workbench, Delphi, Blacktab, VS Code, Python, SQL, Tableau

Smoothstack - McLean, VA (Remote) | Cloud Engineer | 11/2022 - 04/2023

- Automated service operations and application installation using Python and Bash scripts
- Architected and developed reusable infrastructure modules with Terraform and Ansible to deploy applications to ECS and EKS
- Designed and maintained a robust CI/CD pipeline using Jenkins and GitLab to streamline the
 deployment of Java Spring Boot microservices, React/Angular UI, and MySQL database to AWS,
 including automated tests with SonarQube and Terratest

Environment: AWS, Terraform, Ansible, Jenkins, SonarQube, Terratest, Ansible AWX

Vermont Idea Company - Shelburne, VT (Remote) | Systems Software Engineer | 10/2022 - 03/2023

- Maintained and managed systems documentation in Confluence and Software Design Document
- Implemented and converted existing **MATLAB** scripts to **Python**, adjusting the architecture to conform to an object-oriented programming environment
- Analyzed algorithm performance, identified opportunities for optimization and efficiency improvements, and proposed solutions

Environment: Python, MATLAB, Confluence, Jira, XML

CERTIFICATIONS

Terraform Associate (002) | Splunk Core Power User

EDUCATION

MSc in Data Analytics | Western Governors University | Salt Lake City, UT BSc in Computer Science & Accounting | Western Governors University, Salt Lake City, UT